Here, we have an object cat that has two properties: age,
هنا، لدينا كائن "cat" الذي يتضمن خاصيتين: خاصية "age"،
which points to a number two,
وتشير إلى الرقم 2،
and name which points to a string of Bailey.
وخاصية "name" التي تُشير إلى سلسلة "Bailey".
Now let's go ahead and add another property.
دعونا نتقدم الآن ونقوم بإضافة خاصية أخرى.
Let's go ahead and call it, meow,
لنتابع ونُطلق عليها اسم، meow،
and have this point to a function.
ونجعلها تُشير إلى دالة.
You can see that all this function does is just
ويمكنكم رؤية أن كل ما تفعلوه هذه الدالة مجرد
print the string meow to the console, just click console.log.
طباعة السلسلة "meow" إلى وحدة التحكم، انقروا فوق console.log فحسب.
So, just like how cat.age allows us to access the property age,
لذلك، تمامًا مثلما تُتيح لنا "cat.age" الوصول إلى الخاصية "age"،
gives you a value of two,
التي تُعطيكم القيمة 2،
you can check out the value of meow property on cat,
فإنه بإمكانكم التحقق من قيمة الخاصية "meow" في الكائن "cat"،
and see that it is indeed a function.
ولاحظوا أنها دالة في الواقع.
So now, to call this function,
الآن، لاستدعاء هذه الدالة،
to invoke this function,
لطلب هذه الدالة،
patch the meow property,
لتصحيح الخاصية "meow"،
all we have to do is just attach parentheses at the end of it,
كل ما يجب أن نفعله هو إدراج أقواس في نهايتها،
just as if it's any other function that we're invoking.
كما لو كانت أي دالة أخرى نقوم باستدعائها.
So, cat.meow logs meow as a string to the console.
لذلك، تقوم "cat.meow" بتسجيل "meow" باعتبارها سلسلة إلى وحدة التحكم.
Excellent. Let's refresh the console.
ممتاز! دعونا نُحدِّث وحدة التحكم.
Now, let's go ahead and add another property to this cat object.
الآن، لنتابع ونُضيف خاصية أخرى إلى الكائن "cat" هذا.
We added a new greet property to the cat object,
لقد أضفنا خاصية جديدة وهي "greet" إلى الكائن "cat" هذا،
which points to another function, but this time,
والذي يُشير إلى دالة أخرى، لكن هذه المرة،
the function takes in a single argument, a person.
تتضمن الدالة وسيطة واحدة وهي "person".
So, what this function does is just print out hello,
لذلك، ما تفعله هذه الدالة هي طباعة كلمة "hello"
person's name, exclamation mark right to the console. Let's check it out.
واسم الشخص وعلامة تعجب على يمين وحدة التحكم. لنراجع هذا.
Cat.greet. Now, within the parenthesis, let's pass it as string.
"Cat.greet.&lrm;" الآن، داخل الأقواس، لنقم بتمريرها كسلسلة.
We'll just say my name, Andrew.
وسأقول فقط أن اسمي "Andrew".
Excellent. So, invoking greet on this cat object,
ممتاز! لذا فإن استدعاء "greet" في هذا الكائن "cat"،
while passing in a single argument,
خلال التمرير في وسيطة واحدة،
Andrew, logs out "Hello Andrew!" And there you have it.
"Andrew"، يُخرج "Hello Andrew!" وهي لديكم الآن.